[The Inextricable Destiny]
[المصير الذي لا ينفصم]
[Side Story]
[قصة جانبية]
You stayed up all night reading books.
لقد سهرت طوال الليل لقراءة الكتب.
Where are you going now?
إلى أين أنت ذاهب الآن؟
I want to go and see
أريد أن أذهب وأرى
if some stories
إذا كانت بعض القصص
are true.
صحيحة.
You should rest before you go.
يجب أن ترتاح قبل أن تذهب.
Young Master, it's time to take your medicine.
السيد الشاب، حان الوقت لتناول الدواء الخاص بك.
After my death,
بعد وفاتي،
if I'm not buried in the Rong family's cemetery,
إذا لم أدفن في مقبرة عائلة رونغ،
will they blame me?
هل سيلومونني؟
Young Master, you're just not fully healed from the old injuries.
أيها السيد الشاب، أنت لم تشفى تمامًا من جروحك القديمة.
You'll be fine.
ستكون بخير.
My old injuries.
جروحي القديمة .
They were so severe.
لقد كانوا شديدين جدًا.
Why did I heal?
لماذا شفيت؟
Madam always has some
سيدتي دائما لديها بعض
rare treasures that we don't know about.
الكنوز النادرة التي لا نعرف عنها.
And she knows methods we are unaware of.
وهي تعرف أساليب لا ندركها.
She was able to cure you before.
لقد كانت قادرة على علاجك من قبل.
It's not surprising
فإنه ليس من المستغرب
that she healed you again.
أنها شفيت لك مرة أخرى.
Young Master.
المعلم الصغير.
Master.
يتقن.
A painter named Huang is here.
هناك رسام اسمه هوانغ.
He said he was your friend.
وقال أنه كان صديقك.
He is waiting outside the door to see you.
إنه ينتظر خارج الباب لرؤيتك.
Mom.
أم.
There's something I must tell you.
هناك شيء يجب أن أخبرك به.
Gui's mother.
والدة غوي.
Miss Jiu.
الآنسة جيو.
I hunted some chicken here.
لقد اصطدت بعض الدجاج هنا.
Would you like these two?
هل ترغب في هذين؟
I'm really sorry, Miss Jiu.
أنا آسف حقًا يا آنسة جيو.
I twisted my hand chopping wood recently.
لقد لويت يدي أثناء تقطيع الخشب مؤخرًا.
Gui has been cooking these past few days.
كان واجهة المستخدم الرسومية يطبخ في الأيام القليلة الماضية.
I, I really can't help you with that.
أنا، أنا حقا لا أستطيع مساعدتك في ذلك.
I suggest you ask someone else.
أقترح عليك أن تسأل شخص آخر.
The strange woman they mentioned is here.
المرأة الغريبة التي ذكروها موجودة هنا.
It's here. Right here.
إنه هنا.  هنا.
She's clearly an old woman but she's pregnant.
من الواضح أنها امرأة عجوز لكنها حامل.
Doesn't that make her a demon?
ألا يجعلها ذلك شيطانة؟
Totally.
تماما.
It's here.
إنه هنا.
How disgraceful.
كم هو مشين.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Young Master, just let me.
السيد الشاب، فقط اسمح لي.
I added something
أضفت شيئا
from the booklet
من الكتيب
in the tea,
في الشاي،
so that someone as cute and smart
بحيث يكون شخص لطيف وذكي
as me can accompany you.
كما أستطيع أن أرافقك.
If one day I'm gone…
إذا رحلت يوما...
Go to Mount Wuhua.
اذهب إلى جبل Wuhua.
Mount Wuhua?
جبل ووهوا؟
I need to go to Mount Wuhua as soon as possible.
أحتاج للذهاب إلى Mount Wuhua في أقرب وقت ممكن.
Madam.
سيدتي.
Madam. Jiuling is…
سيدتي.  جيولينغ هو ...
You!
أنت!
Madam.
سيدتي.
As long as you can save her and the child,
طالما يمكنك إنقاذها والطفل،
I am willing
انا أرغب
to do anything in return.
لفعل أي شيء في المقابل.
Only that disciple of mine would be so silly.
فقط ذلك التلميذ لي سيكون سخيفًا جدًا.
She sacrificed her own life just to let you live.
لقد ضحت بحياتها فقط لتسمح لك بالعيش.
Madam.
سيدتي.
The Pipa Zui in her body can only be used once.
لا يمكن استخدام Pipa Zui الموجود في جسدها إلا مرة واحدة.
Killing you won't help.
قتلك لن يفيد
No…
لا…
Are you sure?
هل أنت متأكد؟
Tell me.
أخبرني.
If I can't make both of them live,
إذا لم أتمكن من جعل كل منهما يعيش،
who do you choose?
الذي تختارين؟
Madam.
سيدتي.
If you can save her,
إذا كنت تستطيع إنقاذها،
I can accept having no children in my life,
أستطيع أن أتقبل عدم وجود أطفال في حياتي،
as long as He Jiuling is with me.
طالما أنه Jiuling معي.
Even if she is no longer young and beautiful?
حتى لو لم تعد شابة وجميلة؟
In Nanjiang,
في نانجيانغ،
I once told a story about a sword master.
لقد رويت ذات مرة قصة عن سيد السيف.
That sword master
هذا سيد السيف
was actually my mother.
كانت في الواقع والدتي.
My father and her exchanged letters
تبادل والدي معها الرسائل
and gradually fell in love.
ووقع في الحب تدريجياً.
Even if every time the result was safe,
حتى لو كانت النتيجة آمنة في كل مرة،
he still got worried.
لا يزال يشعر بالقلق.
So,
لذا،
he stopped doing divinations
توقف عن القيام بالعرافة
or replying to her letters,
أو الرد على رسائلها
because my father went to find her
لأن والدي ذهب للعثور عليها
and married her.
وتزوجها.
He wanted to be there for her in every battle
أراد أن يكون بجانبها في كل معركة
and accompany her day by day.
ومرافقتها يوما بعد يوم.
He was her own fortuneteller
لقد كان عرافًا لها
and peace amulet.
وتميمة السلام.
So,
لذا،
just like what you asked me before
تماما مثل ما سألتني من قبل
about if He Jiuling lost or died,
حول ما إذا كان هو جيولينغ قد فقد أو مات،
you ask me now,
تسألني الآن،
if she's old and not pretty,
إذا كانت كبيرة في السن وليست جميلة،
what would I do? My answer
ما الذي يمكنني فعله؟  إجابتي
will always be the same as my father's.
سوف يكون دائما نفس والدي.
I will spend my life with her even if death separates us.
سأقضي حياتي معها ولو فرقنا الموت.
When I went to Nanjiang,
عندما ذهبت إلى نانجيانغ،
I was prepared for this.
لقد كنت على استعداد لهذا.
She guards the home and the country,
وهي تحرس الوطن والوطن
and I will guard her.
وسوف أحرسها.
Hurry up.
أسرع - بسرعة.
We are almost there.
نحن تقريبا هناك.
- Jiuling is here? - Yes.
- جيولينغ هنا؟  - نعم.
- Go. - Lead the way.
- يذهب.  - قيادة الطريق.
Master.
يتقن.
Is that really you?
هل هذا انت حقا؟
If it's not me,
إذا لم يكن أنا،
who else would come to collect your body?
من غيرك سيأتي ليأخذ جسدك؟
What are you doing here?
ما الذي تفعله هنا؟
Now
الآن
is not the time to catch up.
ليس هذا هو الوقت المناسب للحاق بالركب.
Look at you.
انظر لحالك.
It's only been a few months since we saw each other,
لقد مرت بضعة أشهر فقط منذ أن رأينا بعضنا البعض،
and you've wrecked your body.
ولقد دمرت جسمك.
I told you in Nanjiang.
قلت لك في نانجيانغ.
You're surviving on Pipa Zui.
أنت تعيش على Pipa Zui.
How could you give that up?
كيف يمكن أن تتخلى عن ذلك؟
If anything happens to you,
إذا حدث أي شيء لك،
how would I…
كيف لي…
What would I do?
ما الذي يمكنني فعله؟
Master.
يتقن.
You know everything.
أنت تعرف كل شيء.
Drink it.
اشربه.
I had no other choice.
لم يكن لدي أي خيار آخر.
I was at my wits' end.
كنت في الذكاء نهايتي.
I couldn't…
لم أستطع…
I couldn't just watch him go and do nothing.
لم أستطع أن أشاهده وهو يذهب ولا يفعل شيئًا.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
You say you're sorry,
تقول أنك آسف،
but if you had to make the choice again,
ولكن إذا كان عليك أن تقوم بالاختيار مرة أخرى،
you'd do the same.
ستفعل الشيء نفسه.
The men in this world
الرجال في هذا العالم
are no good.
ليست جيدة.
Once you're dead and gone,
بمجرد أن تموت وتذهب،
he can remember you for a while,
يمكنه أن يتذكرك لفترة من الوقت،
but not forever.
ولكن ليس إلى الأبد.
When you're but a skeleton,
عندما تكون مجرد هيكل عظمي،
he's living a carefree and happy life.
إنه يعيش حياة سعيدة خالية من الهموم.
I'd rather he didn't remember me.
أفضل ألا يتذكرني.
You…
أنت…
He can be carefree,
يمكن أن يكون غير مبالي،
happy,
سعيد،
and fall in love with another person.
وتقع في حب شخص آخر.
As long as he is happy in his lifetime,
طالما أنه سعيد في حياته،
everything will be fine.
كل شي سيصبح على مايرام.
You're so naive.
أنت ساذج جدًا.
You're so silly.
أنت جدا سخيف.
I've been silly all my life.
لقد كنت سخيفا طوال حياتي.
And I accept it.
وأنا أقبل ذلك.
There's no turning back in life.
ليس هناك عودة إلى الوراء في الحياة.
We all have to move on.
علينا جميعا أن نمضي قدما.
I don't have much time left.
ليس لدي الكثير من الوقت المتبقي.
The only thing I can't let go
الشيء الوحيد الذي لا أستطيع تركه
is the baby in my belly.
هو الطفل في بطني.
He is very strong.
هو قوي جدا.
He has accompanied me so far
لقد رافقني حتى الآن
on such a difficult journey,
في مثل هذه الرحلة الصعبة،
but he is still here.
لكنه لا يزال هنا.
He is truly a miracle.
إنه حقا معجزة.
He must long to open his eyes
يجب عليه أن يفتح عينيه طويلاً
and take a look at this world.
وإلقاء نظرة على هذا العالم.
I have no other wish
ليس لدي رغبة أخرى
but for you to think of a way to save him.
ولكن عليك أن تفكر في طريقة لإنقاذه.
This is indeed a miracle.
هذه حقا معجزة.
Perhaps this time,
وربما هذه المرة،
the miracle can save you.
المعجزة يمكن أن تنقذك.
There's no more Pipa Zui in your body.
لم يعد هناك بيبا زوي في جسمك.
but there might still be some in his.
ولكن قد لا يزال هناك بعض في بلده.
You said he has accompanied you on such a difficult journey,
لقد قلت أنه رافقك في هذه الرحلة الصعبة،
and he's still here.
وهو لا يزال هنا.
Have you ever thought that it is because of Pipa Zui?
هل فكرت يوما أن ذلك بسبب بيبا زوي؟
With your current physical condition,
مع حالتك البدنية الحالية،
all I can do is make him meet you as soon as possible.
كل ما يمكنني فعله هو أن أجعله يقابلك في أقرب وقت ممكن.
And then try to find a way
ثم حاول أن تجد طريقة
to extract the remaining Pipa Zui
لاستخراج ما تبقى من Pipa Zui
from his body.
من جسده.
No, I don't want him to go through that pain.
لا، لا أريده أن يعاني من هذا الألم.
Ling.
لينغ.
He grew up with Pipa Zui.
نشأ مع بيبا زوي.
The fact that he has survived this way
حقيقة أنه نجا بهذه الطريقة
has made him
لقد جعله
an existence different from others.
وجود مختلف عن الآخرين.
Even if we extract the Pipa Zui
حتى لو استخرجنا البيبا زوي
from his body,
من جسده،
he wouldn't experience the pain like everyone else,
لن يشعر بالألم مثل أي شخص آخر،
and he would be okay.
وسيكون بخير.
He Jiuling.
هو جيولينغ.
I've only read a sentence
لقد قرأت جملة واحدة فقط
about this kind of person in the records
عن هذا النوع من الأشخاص في السجلات
of my master's master on Mount Wuhua.
من سيدتي على جبل Wuhua.
He is a miracle.
إنه معجزة.
Trust me.
ثق بي.
Go to the drugstore and buy me ginseng and danggui. Hurry up.
اذهب إلى الصيدلية واشتري لي الجينسنغ والدانغوي.  أسرع - بسرعة.
Yes.
نعم.
Here.
هنا.
Cheers?
هتافات؟
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
Come on.
تعال.
Shangyuan, TianTing, Taiwei Palace.
شانغيوان، تيان تينغ، قصر تايوي.
Dazzling stellar phenomena tread the firmament.
ظواهر نجمية مبهرة تطأ السماء.
Duanmen is just one of the gates.
Duanmen هي مجرد واحدة من البوابات.
The guards stand in the east and west.
يقف الحراس في الشرق والغرب.
Master, I have a question here.
أستاذ عندي سؤال هنا
Now is not the time for queries.
الآن ليس الوقت المناسب للاستفسارات.
If you have questions,
إذا كان لديك أسئلة،
and you still don't understand them after I finish the lecture,
وما زلت لم تفهمهم بعد أن أنهي المحاضرة،
you can ask them.
يمكنك أن تسألهم.
But asking them now is the same.
لكن سؤالهم الآن هو نفسه.
Because I never understood it,
لأني لم أفهم ذلك أبداً
and I am very anxious.
وأنا قلقة للغاية.
Here, about the guards.
هنا عن الحراس.
Where are your manners?
أين أخلاقك؟
As a fortuneteller,
كعرافة،
you mustn't be anxious
يجب أن لا تكون قلقا
or impatient for success.
أو الصبر على النجاح.
- Young Master. - You should be calm and composed at all times.
- المعلم الصغير.  - يجب أن تكون هادئًا ومتماسكًا في جميع الأوقات.
Just like our Master.
تماما مثل سيدنا.
Just like the Master, occasionally being impatient
تمامًا مثل السيد، أحيانًا ينفد صبره
is also normal.
أمر طبيعي أيضًا.
Young Master, hurry up.
السيد الشاب، اسرع.
How did you get in?
كيف تحصل في؟
I haven't forgiven you yet. Leave.
لم أسامحك بعد.  يترك.
Madam, let me wait here today.
سيدتي، اسمحوا لي أن أنتظر هنا اليوم.
Go away, you're an eyesore.
اذهب بعيدا، أنت قذى البصر.
Madam.
سيدتي.
Leave.
يترك.
Okay, I'll leave.
حسنًا، سأغادر.
It's already daylight.
لقد حل ضوء النهار بالفعل.
How come there is no movement inside?
كيف لا توجد حركة في الداخل؟
Young Master.
المعلم الصغير.
They're gone.
لقد رحلوا.
Young master, they left through the side door.
السيد الشاب، لقد غادروا من الباب الجانبي.
Young master.
المعلم الصغير.
After several years of entanglement,
وبعد عدة سنوات من التشابك،
I think you all understand the meaning of "Deep love hurts".
أعتقد أنكم جميعًا تفهمون معنى "الحب العميق مؤلم".
He Jiuling is fine.
هو جيولينغ على ما يرام.
I'll take her away.
سوف آخذها بعيدا.
I only wish that you two
أتمنى فقط أنكما
would bid farewell and let go.
سوف توديع وترك.
Take a look.
إلق نظرة.
Not bad.
ليس سيئًا.
Everyone says how lovely the water towns in the South are.
الجميع يقول كم هي جميلة المدن المائية في الجنوب.
The liveliness and prosperity here
الحيوية والازدهار هنا
are certainly no less than in the capital city.
هي بالتأكيد ليست أقل مما كانت عليه في العاصمة.
Tomorrow, are we going to Liuzhou?
غدا، هل سنذهب إلى ليوتشو؟
Your Majesty, not Liuzhou, it's Chudi.
صاحب الجلالة، ليس ليوتشو، إنه تشودي.
Why Chudi? Who arranged this?
لماذا تشودي؟  من رتب هذا؟
The Princess heard that Your Majesty wanted to make a secret visit,
سمعت الأميرة أن جلالتك يريد القيام بزيارة سرية،
and she especially wrote a letter inviting us.
وقد كتبت بشكل خاص رسالة تدعونا فيها.
No, we're not going.
لا، لن نذهب.
Chu must be planning to torture
يجب أن يكون تشو يخطط للتعذيب
these courtiers following me.
هؤلاء الخدم يتبعونني.
Yes, I will inform the others and change the route to Liuzhou tonight.
نعم، سأبلغ الآخرين وأغير الطريق إلى ليوتشو الليلة.
Look.
ينظر.
This is for you.
هذا لك.
Chu might be a bit unruly.
قد يكون تشو جامحًا بعض الشيء.
But what she said is not wrong.
لكن ما قالته ليس خطأ.
The women in the South
المرأة في الجنوب
are indeed more passionate and interesting
هم في الواقع أكثر عاطفية ومثيرة للاهتمام
than the women in the capital city.
من النساء في العاصمة.
Little Uncle.
العم الصغير.
Can I ask you for a favor?
هل استطيع ان اسئلك لخدمة؟
Did you call me Little Uncle?
هل ناديتني بالعم الصغير؟
Old Uncle.
العم القديم.
Can I ask you for a favor?
هل استطيع ان اسئلك لخدمة؟
Not Uncle, I…
لا يا عم أنا...
If you insist on a title, call me brother.
إذا كنت تصر على اللقب، اتصل بي أخي.
Alright, old brother.
حسنًا يا أخي القديم
Everything about the south is good,
كل شيء في الجنوب جيد
except for the children
باستثناء الأطفال
who are a bit sillier than those in the capital.
الذين هم أكثر سخافة قليلا من تلك الموجودة في العاصمة.
Tell me, what do you need?
قل لي، ماذا تحتاج؟
Can you help me carry this?
هل يمكنك مساعدتي في حمل هذا؟
My house is still some distance from here,
منزلي لا يزال على بعد مسافة من هنا،
and I really can't carry it anymore.
وأنا حقا لا أستطيع تحمله بعد الآن.
Why are you out here at this age?
لماذا أنت هنا في هذا العمر؟
Where are your parents?
أين والديك؟
Why are you asking about my family?
لماذا تسأل عن عائلتي؟
I'm just asking.
انا اسالك فقط.
It's right for you not to tell me.
من حقك أن لا تخبرني.
At such a young age, if you encounter bad people,
في هذه السن المبكرة، إذا واجهت أشخاصًا سيئين،
it will be dangerous.
سيكون خطيرا.
Bad people?
اناس سيئون؟
I'm not afraid of bad people.
أنا لا أخاف من الناس السيئين.
Why aren't you scared?
لماذا لست خائفا؟
You're just a little girl.
أنت مجرد فتاة صغيرة.
Aren't you afraid that I'll kidnap you?
ألا تخافين أن أخطفك؟
I'd like to see you try.
أود أن أراك تحاول.
You're pretty tough, huh?
أنت قوي جدًا، هاه؟
No, in the whole family, I am the weakest.
لا، أنا الأضعف في العائلة بأكملها.
Wang Dequan, this young girl might be a little silly,
وانغ ديكوان، قد تكون هذه الفتاة الصغيرة سخيفة بعض الشيء،
but she's quite interesting.
لكنها مثيرة للاهتمام للغاية.
Yes, yes.
نعم نعم.
Come on, let's go. I'll take it.
هيا بنا نذهب.  أنا أعتبر.
Take this.
خد هذا.
Okay, let's go.
حسنا دعنا نذهب.
What's in this?
ماذا يوجد في هذا؟
There's a noise.
هناك ضجيج.
A cricket?
لعبة الكريكيت؟
No.
لا.
A scarab beetle?
خنفساء الجعران؟
But it doesn't seem like it.
ولكن لا يبدو الأمر كذلك.
An owl?
بومة؟
There's such a bug?
هناك مثل هذا الخلل؟
No, there isn't.
لا، لا يوجد.
Mom said only I could raise it.
قالت أمي أنني فقط أستطيع رفعه.
Don't open it.
لا تفتحه.
Now you believe me, right?
الآن أنت تصدقني، أليس كذلك؟
I am not afraid of bad people.
أنا لا أخاف من الناس السيئين.
It's like you've drunk a hundred jars of wine.
يبدو الأمر كما لو كنت قد شربت مائة جرة من النبيذ.
Make way. Move.
أصنع طريقا.  يتحرك.
I'm not afraid of bad people.
أنا لا أخاف من الناس السيئين.
I'm not a bad guy.
أنا لست رجل سيء.
I didn't do it on purpose.
لم أفعل ذلك عن قصد.
Mom.
أم.
Rong'er.
رونغ.
Come on.
تعال.
What about my child?
ماذا عن طفلي؟
Young master, are you alright?
السيد الشاب، هل أنت بخير؟
What… what about me?
ماذا...ماذا عني؟
♫ Looking back, I see you waiting ♫
♫ بالنظر إلى الوراء، أرى أنك تنتظر ♫
♫ Our lives are filled with joy and sorrow ♫
♫ حياتنا مليئة بالفرح والحزن ♫
♫ The longings crystalize into a bright galaxy ♫
♫ تتبلور الأشواق في مجرة ​​مشرقة ♫
♫ You turned around quietly and closed the marriage book ♫
♫ استدرت بهدوء وأغلقت دفتر الزواج ♫
♫ Asking how many stars there are in the sky ♫
♫ السؤال عن عدد النجوم الموجودة في السماء ♫
♫ Our lives are filled with joy and sorrow ♫
♫ حياتنا مليئة بالفرح والحزن ♫
♫ The longings crystalize into a bright galaxy ♫
♫ تتبلور الأشواق في مجرة ​​مشرقة ♫
♫ Gently I stroke the zither, waiting for a passerby like you ♫
♫ أعزف على آلة القانون بلطف، في انتظار أحد المارة مثلك ♫
♫ Turns out you are my inextricable destiny ♫
♫ تبين أنك قدري الذي لا ينفصل ♫
♫ Under the setting sun in dusk ♫
♫ تحت غروب الشمس في الغسق ♫
♫ I travel far for thousands of miles ♫
♫ أسافر بعيدًا لآلاف الأميال ♫
♫ Playing the zither under the moonlight ♫
♫ العزف على آلة القانون تحت ضوء القمر ♫
♫ The drinks won't let me forget ♫
♫ المشروبات لن تجعلني أنسى ♫
♫ The longing I write down for you ♫
♫ الشوق الذي أكتبه لك ♫
♫ Our fate is written on paper ♫
♫ مصيرنا مكتوب على الورق ♫
♫ Just like the strongest wine ♫
♫ تمامًا مثل أقوى أنواع النبيذ ♫
♫ There's no escape for destiny ♫
♫ ليس هناك مفر من القدر ♫
♫ Looking back, I see you waiting ♫
♫ بالنظر إلى الوراء، أرى أنك تنتظر ♫
♫ Our lives are filled with joy and sorrow ♫
♫ حياتنا مليئة بالفرح والحزن ♫
♫ The longings crystalize into a bright galaxy ♫
♫ تتبلور الأشواق في مجرة ​​مشرقة ♫
♫ You turned around quietly and closed the marriage book ♫
♫ استدرت بهدوء وأغلقت دفتر الزواج ♫
♫ Asking how many stars there are in the sky ♫
♫ السؤال عن عدد النجوم الموجودة في السماء ♫
♫ The longing I write down for you ♫
♫ الشوق الذي أكتبه لك ♫
♫ Our fate is written on paper ♫
♫ مصيرنا مكتوب على الورق ♫
♫ Just like the strongest wine ♫
♫ تمامًا مثل أقوى أنواع النبيذ ♫
♫ There's no escape for destiny ♫
♫ ليس هناك مفر من القدر ♫
♫ Looking back, I see you waiting ♫
♫ بالنظر إلى الوراء، أرى أنك تنتظر ♫
♫ Our lives are filled with joy and sorrow ♫
♫ حياتنا مليئة بالفرح والحزن ♫
♫ The longings crystalize into a bright galaxy ♫
♫ تتبلور الأشواق في مجرة ​​مشرقة ♫
♫ Gently I stroke the zither, waiting for a passerby like you ♫
♫ أعزف على آلة القانون بلطف، في انتظار أحد المارة مثلك ♫
♫ Turns out you are my inextricable destiny ♫
♫ تبين أنك قدري الذي لا ينفصل ♫